Good afternoon.
Welcome to the January 6, 2026 finance
committee meeting. Want to remind
everyone to please turn off their cell
phones or move them to vibrate or mute
any devices they might bring.
When making public comment, clearly
identify yourself, please. To make
public comment online, use the raise
hand function online.
In person,
point approach the podium and please
turn on the microphone and adjust it to
where you can uh speak clearly into it.
Uh the public uh there is no additional
business to be discussed following
completion of this agenda. Clerk, please
read the first item. Number eight,
ordinance, third reading, defining the
terms and conditions of employment for
sworn officers of the Cheyenne Police
Department for January 2026 until the
end of fiscal year 2026.
>> Staff report. All right, Mr. Chairman,
members of the committee, Captain David
Jane, Shy Police Department. What you
have before you is a repeal and replace
ordinance of our terms and conditions.
The only substantive change in here is
the 3% increase uh the cost of living
adjustment uh which has already been
funded and and approved through that and
that's reflected on exhibit B within
this uh contract. And I stand for any
questions.
>> Any questions for the captain?
Hearing none. Any public comment?
Any public comment online?
No. Uh, may I have a motion, please?
>> Um, Mr. Chairman, I move to approve on
third and final reading.
>> Moved by Moody.
>> Mr. Chairman, I second that motion.
>> Second by Wolf. Uh, any discussion from
the committee?
Hearing none. All those in favor?
>> I
>> I. The recommendation uh for the me for
Monday's meeting will be to approve on
third and final reading. Next item,
please.
>> Number 16. Resolution approving a
sponsorship by Bison Beverage for
Cheyenne Frontier Days events occurring
July 17th through July 26th of 2026,
July 23rd through August 1st, 2027, and
July 21st through July 30th of 2028.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, members of the committee,
Kylie Soden, city clerk. The item before
you is a resolution that approves a
three-year sponsorship between Bison
Beverage and Cheyenne Frontier Days for
2026, 2027, and 2028. Approval of the
licensing authority is required under
Wyoming statute 12-5-42,
which regulates transactions between
alcohol industry representatives and
retail liquor license holders. Tram
Frontier Days qualifies for the
statutory exception that allows this
type of sponsorship as they are
nonprofit taxexempt organization that
has operated continuously for more than
two years. And I am available for any
questions you may have.
>> Any questions, Mr. Escoel?
>> Oh, sorry.
>> Questions. Is there a
representative of uh Cheyenne Frontier
Day is here to speak to tell us a little
bit more about this.
Tom Hig Cheyen Frontier Days. Um Mr.
Chairman, I think uh this is pretty
self-explanatory. It's been a
relationship we've had for a long time
with the Louiswis family and bison
beverage. Um, but uh we sure appreciate
your support on on approving that
sponsorship.
>> Any questions?
Thank you. Hearing none.
>> Any public comment?
Any public comment online?
Hearing none. May I have a motion? Mr.
Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Second.
Moved by Esabel, seconded by Wolf. Any
discussion from committee?
Hearing none. All those in favor?
>> I I
>> I.
>> The recommendation for Monday's meeting
will be to adopt. Next item, please.
Number 17, resolution adopting the
amended 2025 to 2027 city of Cheyenne
comprehensive consolidated plan and the
amended amended 2025 annual action plan
as prepared by the Cheyenne Housing and
Community Development Office and setting
the public comment period and public
hearings for the plans.
>> Good afternoon.
>> Good afternoon. Um my name is Amy Gorby.
I'm the community development manager
for the city's housing and community
development division. Um I'm here to
provide a staff report and answer
questions about the amendments included
in the 2025 to 2027 consolidated plan
and the 2025 annual action plan. Um the
purpose of the amendment is to repurpose
returned and available CDBG funds to
address identified community needs. And
I'm here to stand for questions.
Any questions?
>> M
>> Mr. Wolf,
>> Mr. Chairman, thank you. Um,
what's the best way to try and
understand what it is you guys do?
[laughter]
Yes, you obviously have a lot of
business between the council and with
the council and uh are a significant
part of uh the city's operations and so
maybe I just need to come over your
office and uh sit down and uh you can
explain it to me.
>> Um Mr. [clears throat] Chairman through
you to Councilwoman Wolf. I would love
that. Um, CDBG is the community
development block grant and it is a HUD
grant, housing and urban development
federal grant that the city has received
annually since the mid 1970s. Our status
is an entitlement city. And because of
that, based on our population of low to
moderate income residents, we qualify
for funding every year. And I'm the
grant manager for those funds. That's
the sort of cliffnote version.
M
>> Mr. chairman, just a quick followup.
>> Sure.
>> Um,
well, thank you. Um,
>> my pleasure.
>> I've heard great things about you and
your operation. Ha, have have you been
impacted by all of the changes that have
occurred this past year in federal
funding, and has that affected uh uh
significantly um your operations or the
city's ability to provide services?
>> U Mr. Mr. Chairman, through you again to
Councilman Wolf. Um, we have been
impacted, sir, um, very much. The the
closure of the federal government
resulted in us losing access to our
region 8 HUD representative in Denver
and um, I have regular consultations
with the rep regarding changes to the
action plan. Um, additionally, um, the
city is required to sign, um, an annual
SF424
form for HUD. And what that includes is,
um, statements of what the city, um,
will abide by, what laws, and there have
been some new requirements through HUD,
um, that have come down from some of the
new administration executive orders. Um,
unfortunately there's not a guid a lot
of guidance yet on how that should be
interpreted with the way you grant money
to subreients. So we lost a few
subreients this year because we were
unsure if those were um eligible
activities based on the new
requirements. So um it's been a lot of
just rolling with it for lack of a
better word. Yeah.
Thank you for asking.
>> Thanks.
Further question, Mr. Escoel.
>> Mr. Chair, I just going to elaborate a
little bit more that uh as the
representative from the city council to
the advisory council, the CDGB is uh we
meet the first Wednesday of every month
4:00
right next door here. So, tomorrow
welcome to attend.
>> Yeah, please join.
>> Mr. Moody.
>> Uh thank you, Mr. Uh thank you, ma'am.
So just uh so the public understands the
biggest change is that acquisition. Am I
correct? That's the biggest change on
here. That's what we're voting on. Mr.
Chairman, through you to Councilman
Moody. That is correct. That is the
largest change in the consolidated plan
and the amended action plans. Um we had
a few smaller uh grant awards to um some
subreients and we were unsure if those
were eligible activities. So with the
funds that were unused, we reallocated
them to some of the um already funded
activities and increased the award
amount and then we added the needs um
food program because we had additional
funds.
>> Thank you, ma'am. No further questions.
>> Thank you. Um do we have any uh
representative here today that wants to
make a comment? Hearing
none. Um the public comment. Um well the
same thing. Um
welcome
a little bit maybe.
>> Good afternoon Mr. Chairman, members of
the committee. Dan Dors, executive
director for Habitat for Humanity of
Laramie County. I'm just here to speak
on uh support of the uh consolidation
plan. Amy has been doing wonderful
things with the CDBG program, especially
under the circumstances and the
challenges. So, uh, just here to lend my
support and also give an example of how
the CDBG program has been used in the
past. We used to utilize um the program
for home repairs and and home
modifications for individuals who needed
to age and place safely in their homes.
And just um on December 23rd, we were
able to close on a home and put a
homeowner in a BL blighted blighted and
vacant property that we purchased and
rehabilitated with CDBG funds. So um it
was a small house on the south side that
we were able to put a single mom and a
daughter in and they were able to spend
the holidays in that new home thanks to
the CDBG program. So we support uh the
CDBG and Amy's work and the city's
support for this program as well. Thank
you very much and I stand for any
questions.
>> Mr. Wolf, Mr. Chairman, thank you.
[clears throat] Mr. Dorch, it's
wonderful to see you. So, [laughter]
>> you as well. I've
>> been known known you and and uh of
course your wife for a long time and so
I just wanted to express my appreciation
to you for all the work that Habitat
does and and your connections with this
council and the and the city government
and and I'm glad to hear that you have a
strong working relationship with uh Amy
and her programs.
>> Mr. Chair, through you to Mr. Uh,
Councilman Wolf, thank you, Mr. Wolf.
It's great to see you as well, and thank
you for that. We appreciate that, and we
just appreciate the city's uh,
willingness to help with Habitat and the
nonprofits here and understand the
challenges that the the nonprofit
community faces and and the need for
affordable housing and and the other
things the CDBG program helps
facilitate. So, thank you.
Any further public comment either here
or online?
seem to be any. Um, could I have a
motion, please?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to adopt.
>> Moved by Esabel.
>> Second.
>> Seconded by Wolf. Further discussion
from the committee.
>> Mr. Chair,
>> Mr. Esabel,
>> just want to point out and usually once
a year I'll make this comment is that
there is a difference between affordable
housing and lowincome housing. And I
just want to make sure that we don't put
those two in the same categories. So I
know a lot of times when we talk about
low-income housing, people get uh the
wrong idea about um what we're trying to
do and this is not that.
>> Uh Mr. Moody.
>> Yep. Uh thank you. I think for the
report um and for the public on page 18
worth the amendment to this uh that
acquisition is still associated with
that private equity firm and as
everybody knows my feeling on private
equity firms residential housing. I'm
not going to repeat it and I would
encourage people in the media to
investigate more. A lot of small
journalists have done that. That's why
I'll be a no vote. Everything else is
fine, but I can't in good conscience
ever support a private equity firm being
involved in any type of housing. And
most Americans and my constituents are
against that. So that's why. But
appreciate all your hard work. Thank
you.
>> Thank you. Uh all those in favor?
>> I I
recommendations for Monday's meeting
will be to adopt. Next item, please.
>> Number 18 C. the agreement between the
city of Cheyenne and Ring Central LLC
for providing cloud-based enterprise
telecom services for all city
departments and divisions from the
general fund
>> staff report.
>> Good afternoon uh Tylen city IT uh Mr.
Chair and members of the committee. Um,
the request for approval you have before
you is concerning an agreement between
the city of Cheyenne and Ring Central
LLC.
Um, the city's current on premise phone
system has reached end of life as
support for the software has expired and
is no longer being developed by MEL. The
city however does maintain support for
the system temporarily through a third
party provider.
[clears throat]
Excuse me. Um the city IT department has
chosen to go with the ring central cloud
telco products as offers features and
aspects that held weight in the
decision. A short list of those would be
a direct migration path as Mel our
current provider sold Ring Central its
cloud division in 2021.
A former unified communications as a
service partner.
Uh, second on that list would be Ring
Central's cloud solution offers mobility
features that many city employees would
be able to leverage during times of
remote working.
Third on the list, um, compatibility
integration with software solutions we
already use such as Microsoft Teams. So,
uh, users will be able to make phone
calls on their PC without having to have
a physical phone whether at their desk
or using a cell phone. So um flexibility
and and usability is is what we were
after there. Um fourth on the list I'm
going to list here is uh system
resiliency. So this is a cloud product.
Um it being a cloud subscription which
extends flexibility and service uptime
management and availability.
um we pulled some some stats or data off
the internet um that was reported by
Ring Central and they reported a 99.9%
uptime the last year. So if
[clears throat] you have a internet
connection you can use the system. So
employees from home, employees working
in the building, employees working
wherever
um on vacation um as long as you have
internet access, you can use the city's
phone system with this product. So,
we're excited to to um to report that.
So, um there are any questions? I I can
try and answer the best I can.
>> Any questions,
>> Mr. Wolf?
>> Mr. Chairman, uh thank you. Um I don't
other than this documents, I really
don't know much about this. What's
what's the timing of of this and are we
in a and we'll be in a transition phase
between them for a period of time?
>> Yeah. So, we've had our current phone
system since 2014.
Um that was a Shorttell system, Shortell
branded system at the time. Mel bought
that system.
Um,
Mel um rebranded Shortell's stuff um for
a number of years and now has made the
choice to kind of discontinue it. Um
we're considered orange customers
because Shortell's colors were orange.
So um they're they're migrating all of
their their stuff either to an on-prem
or a cloud solution. We chose to go with
the cloud solution because of its um
features I just outlined. Um
so time as far as timing goes um uh
support for our current system just
expired. We do have uh someone we can
call like I said um until migration is
done. Um pretty much the city's in a
situation where we're going to have to
change. Um our current installed system
is is
going out. So, it would be, you know, uh
a violation of security and and all of
that if we were to just not do anything.
Um so,
if I were to kind of just maybe guess on
a timeline, um if once this was
approved, um and we could go forward, we
would start um immediately um which
would be part of this quote is the
hardware order. we get phones in to
replace current phones that would be
incompatible with what we need to
migrate to. Um I'm guessing
start of the budget year um we'd have a
pretty good idea on how quickly we could
roll out the system. I don't think it's
going to take long just because of um it
being myel to ring central. There's
already a partnership there that's been
in place for years. So the the migration
path is already vetted in my opinion. So
does that answer your question?
>> Okay.
Any further questions?
Any public comment
either here or online?
No. Okay. May I have a motion, please?
Uh
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount not to exceed $65,000.
>> Second.
>> Moved by Moody, second by Esabel. Any
further discussion from committee?
Hearing? None. All those in favor?
>> I
>> I.
>> The recommendation for Monday's meeting
will be to approve in an amount not to
exceed 65,000. U
last item, please.
Number 19 C, consideration of bid number
S-7-26
for an agreement between the city of
Cheyenne Bull Mountain Electric
Incorporated for the Cheyenne Dumbar
field light installation project from
the 2021 specific purpose option tax
fund development impact fees and wreck
mill grant.
>> Mr. Chair, Jason Sanchez, community
wreck and events. uh before even for
your consideration today is a bid from
uh Pole Mountain Electric to install new
lights at Dunar Field. That's the
softball field in Lions Park. Uh we were
fortunate to receive a $150,000 WCM mill
grant, $150,000 grant match, and we
would cover the $17,000
difference with our community facility
fees. Um I would stand by for any
questions.
>> Thank you. Um,
any questions,
>> Mr. Chairman?
>> Yes.
>> Thank you. Um, Mr. Sanchez, thank you.
Um, I walk by that park every day
practically. Um, and, uh, I've always
thought that you and your crews just
take great care of it and interesting to
see all the new construction around it.
And, um, and if we need new lights, I
take you at your word for that. And so
I'm delighted to to see this and thank
you for your continued attention to it.
>> Thank you, sir.
>> Any uh questions from the public?
Any comments online?
Hearing none. Uh may I have a motion,
please?
>> Mr. Chair, I move to accept the bid not
to exceed $317,000.
>> Second, Mr. Chairman. Moved by Esabel,
seconded by Moody. Um,
excuse me.
>> Larry Wolf.
>> Oops. Larry Wolf.
>> Okay. Want to get that correct, Mr.
Wolf. Um, so, uh, any comments, further
comments from committee,
>> Mr. Chair?
>> Yes.
>> Uh, I played baseball on that field when
I was 14 years old, so that tell you how
old those lights are.
Well, I I think it also tells how old
you are.
>> Well, I ain't going to say that.
>> Okay. Well, uh, in that case, uh, all
those in favor,
>> I
>> The recommendation for Monday night will
be to approve.
Uh, that concludes our agenda for today
and, uh, it concludes my chairmanship of
the finance committee. So, I want to
thank everyone for helping me and
particularly our administrative
assistant and the treasur's office. It's
uh a big responsibility. We spent a lot
of money over the year and uh it is
important that people have that
opportunity to participate and I
appreciate the chairmanship and um
look forward to voting more often. I I
did want to make
uh one comment and that was in regard to
the CDBG.
Um a lot of goods come out of that. I'm
glad we didn't uh end it, which there
was some uh interest in that a number of
years ago. But at the um council meeting
when they brought forward their report,
it was pointed out by the chairman of
the committee that um there is some
really good people working on this that
find a way to sort through those very
complex
uh HUD requirements. And
I'm certainly aware over the years of
all the good that it's done and all the
good that uh we're going to be seeing
here in the future. And u I I really
wonder what the city would do if we
didn't have it. So that's a a program
that uh has proven its worth. So thank
you everybody. Uh that concludes the
meeting.